## **lan Petras**

#### CONTACT

129 Warner Road E17 7DX, London United Kingdom

## **OVERVIEW**

Ridiculously well experienced in all aspects of digital marketing, advertising and web development with a dash of statistical analysis and financial experience. A natural leader with strong management experience both in small SMEs and large FTSE100 multinationals.

A true online and offline marketing and advertising hybrid that combines marketing, modern web development and management experience, ranging from analytics, to creative and to technical in one package. I can make a difference from month one, guaranteed.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Informa (LSE:INF)

2016 - present

E-mail: contact@ianpetras.com

Website: www.ianpetras.com

Mobile: +44 799 000 73 78

Digital Marketing Lead (Experience)

- Responsible with overseeing and auditing all digital marketing channels and processes. Directly involved with the digital transformation across the business.
- Leading the digital marketing and the digital experience effort across 50+ websites and over 20 individual brands globally.
- Managing all SEO and PPC planning, implementing, delivering and drawing insight post-launch.
- Leading the user journey in all things digital, from top of the funnel to SQLs.
- Working with all individual teams on creating, improving and scaling up their respective areas: Social, Content, Paid, SEO, Visual and Branding.
- Maintaining an oversight of all inbound and outbound digital marketing within the business, across APAC, EMEA and the Americas.
- Acting as an ambassador for data-driven marketing all marketing efforts have to answer the 4Ws: Why? - Where? - (To) Whom? - What?
- Would you like to hear more?

## **London Management Centre**

2014 - 2016

Digital Marketing Manager

- Created and lead the marketing department with end to end responsibilities across all channels. Recruited and managed a growing team.
- Directly responsible for creating the yearly marketing plan, creating and implementing the strategy, defining and managing the marketing budget and KPIs.
- Implemented all analytics, reporting channels and other measuring tools across two web properties. Managed all insights, debriefs and direct reports to stakeholders.
- Responsible for all the digital marketing efforts. Directly overseeing a global operation with several EMEA locations, two web properties and a client base of 600+ large companies.
- Successful on-site and off-site SEO from the ground up across two web properties.
- Built and implemented several PPC campaigns across different platforms with an average of 5% CTR. AdWords, Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter.
- Designed and implemented the email marketing strategy. Implemented all the marketing automation tools and logic – maintaining a CTR above industry average.
- Managed and improved the CMS and the front-end of several web properties. Work involved HTML/CSS/PHP/JavaScript requirements.
- Responsible for all outside marketing interaction and networking, marketing affiliates and partners. Directly responsible for managing all external agency work.
- Notable achievement: Delivered an entire marketing department, marketing team and marketing strategy and consequently, a positive ROI across all channels.

E-business Developer

- Responsible for building, implementing and expanding several EMEA markets.
- Heavy SEO and keyword research.
- Client acquisition results based position.
- Improved and built the visibility of an international search engine present in over 90 countries worldwide.
- Notable achievement: New product developed and launched under my guidance.

#### nameOn Nordic - Stockholm

2013 - 2014

Marketing Developer

- E-commerce responsible for five European markets. Directly involved in the digital and online marketing strategy.
- HTML/CSS/PHP/Javascript, Photoshop, Fireworks and Illustrator creative design, producing attractive online campaigns and landing pages.
- Played a crucial role in improving two e-commerce web properties. Conducted marketing A/B tests and onsite SEO.
- Notable achievement: Developed innovative ways for marketing our products online
   from both a technological but also a strategical point of view.

## **Royal North**

2013

## ReadSpeaker

2013

Founder

- Online and offline marketing.
- SEO / PPC / AdWords.
- Creative design.
- Brand management.
- Web and mobile development.

Web Developer (Project based)

- Developing TTS web technologies.
- HTML5/CSS3/Javascript + jQuery/Ajax/PHP.
- Recent projects:
  - Browser extensions with proprietary API.

#### AIESEC Sweden

2012 - 2013

Marketing Assistant

- Brand management and communication strategy creation.
- Responsible with the CMS and the web development efforts (HTML/CSS/JavaScript).
- Reviewing and updating web content on a regular basis.
- Analysis & Reporting: Rigorous campaign analysis and reporting on ROI.
- Worked with on-site and off-site SEO, PPC (AdWords) and analytics.
- Notable achievement: Increased organic traffic by 43% over a 6 month period.

#### M.B.T GmbH Austria

2011 - 2012

Marketing Communications Specialist

- Implemented and coordinated the online strategy for all paid marketing channels.
- Responsible for all affiliate and e-mail marketing operations.
- Produced creative promotional web assets (Photoshop and Illustrator).
- Strategic planning and branding for the entry into the Eastern European market.
- Notable achievements: Launched two new web properties and delivered a complete and successful rebrand.

Nasii Advertising

< 2010

Account Manager / Marketing Internship

**EDUCATION** 

Focus on: Marketing Research, Statistics, Corporate Management, Information and Brand Management, Digital Media, New Media and Digital Marketing.

# BSc (Hons) in Marketing and Communication Science 2008 - 2011 Babes-Bolyai University

Minor in Business Economics. Focus on Marketing, Advertising, Economics, Corporate Communications, Business Development, International Business and Consumer Behaviour.

#### CERTIFICATES

#### **Finance Certificate**

2012

Stanford University

Certificate of accomplishment awarded by Stanford University for successfully completing the Finance course.

## Computer Science (CS50x) Certificate

(expected)

Harvard University edX

Certificate of mastery awarded by Harvard University edX for successful completion of CS50x Computer Science course.

## **Google Analytics and Google AdWords**

2014

Google

Certified Google Analytics and Google AdWords professional.

#### SKILLS

#### Marketing, finance and advertising:

- Digital marketing and media relations experience, plus concept and strategy planning.
- ATL and BTL advertising experience, display advertising, online advertising networks experience (CJ, DoubleClick, AdWords, adCenter, social platforms, etc.)
- Account and brand management. Budget analysis, economics and statistics skills.
- Trained in crisis management, corporate management and communications. High knowledge of information management, manipulation and persuasion techniques.
- Affiliate marketing, e-mail marketing, PPC, SEO, B2B and B2C marketing and several CMS experience (Wordpress, Sitecore, Magento, MODx, Drupal and others).
- CPA, CPC, CPL, CPM models experience. Bid management, keyword research and retargeting experience.
- PPC and PPL campaign creation and implementation experience.
- Social media marketing, analytics experience (Google, Adobe, KissMetrics, Pingdom, GoSquared, etc.)
- Marketing automation experience via Eloqua, Pardot, Marketo, HubSpot.
- Copywriting, graphic design and e-commerce management experience.

#### **Technical skills:**

- Strong web development abilities. Fantastic JS and HTML/PHP/CSS experience.
- Wireframing and UX design. Can code and implement anything from simple landing pages to email marketing campaigns and full-fledged web sites with CMS and online shopping systems integrated.
- Full office suite (any) experience. Statistical analysis via SPSS experience.
- Adobe Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator, Dreamweaver, Fireworks and Premiere experience – creativity comes free of charge.
- Solid Google AdWords, Facebook Ads and Google Analytics experience.
- Other tools: Crazy Egg, SEO Moz, Majestic, SEM Rush, Omniture, SiteImprove, Cision, MeltWater, Sprinklr, HootSuite, Amazon AWS, etc.

#### OTHER EXP.

## Stanford Venture Lab

2013

Finance Community TA (Teaching Assistant)

 Helped students with understanding the concepts taught and the general work requirements. Guest lecturer - Institute for Informatics and Media

 Held lectures pertaining to digital media and marketing for BA and MA students part of the media, economics and HCI (Human-Computer Interaction) departments.

## **LANGUAGES**

- English
- Swedish
- Romanian
- Basic understanding of Spanish, French, Italian.